Finding Aid for Minto-Skelton Papers
William L. Clements Library, University of Michigan
- I: Walter Minto papers
  - 1: Minto correspondence, 1764-1798
    - 10 October 1787, Jamieson
    - 17 October 1787, VanDerbilt
    - 28 January 1788, Drummond (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - 20 February 1788, Anonymous (2)
    - 22 May 1788, Paterson
    - 26 May 1788, James Tod
    - 10 June 1788, Nanny Minto
    - 27 June 1788, Aitchison (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - [February-June 1788], Walter Minto to Drummond
    - 5 July [1788], Drummond
    - 15 December 1788, Collins
    - 21 December 1788, Stone
    - Undated, probably between 1788 and 1789, Walter Minto to [Mary] Skelton (later Mary Minto) (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Undated, probably between 1788 and 1789, Anonymous (3)
    - 5 January 1789, Rush (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - 10 January 1789, Anderson, Thomas
    - 16 January 1789, Drummond
    - 6 February 1789, Hutchison and Vaughan
    - 16 February 1789, Lord Buchan (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - 26 February 1789, Nanny Minto
    - 1 March 1789, Anonymous (5)
    - 2 March 1789, Woodhull
    - 18 March 1789, Fisher (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - 29 March 1789, Drummond
    - 28 April 1789, Mundell
    - 12 June 1789, Thomas Minto
    - 15 June 1789, Ann[i]e Tod
    - 19 June 1789, N[?ichol]nson (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - 29 June 1789, McDonald
    - 6 July 1789, Baynton
    - 1[2] July 1789Walter Minto to Anonymous (2) [= Baynton] (draft or copy)
    - 15 September 1789, Paterson
    - 7 October [probably 1789 though could be later], Minto, Mary (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - 25 October 1789, Drummond
    - 10 November 1789, McDonald
    - 14 December 1789, Irving
    - 18 January 1790, Minto, Walter Sr., to Buist (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - 24 February 1790, Drummond
    - 10 March 1790, Rittenhouse
    - 20 March 1790, Stone
    - 27 March 1790, Lord Buchan (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - 19 July 1790, Drummond
    - 15 November 1790, Rittenhouse
    - 5 March 1791, Kemp (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - 5 March 1791, Mason
    - 27 April 1791, Drummond
    - 25 June 1791, Minto, Thomas
    - 28 June 1791, Lord Buchan
    - 30 July 1791, Minto, Thomas (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - 16 August 1791, Buist
    - 26 September 1791, Rittenhouse
    - 11 November 1791, McDonald
    - 24 March 1792, Rush (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - 6 April 1792, Gale
    - 30 April 1792, Rush
    - 3 May 1792, Hubey (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - 9 May 1792, Rush
    - 25 May 1792, Rittenhouse
    - 28 May 1792, McDonald
    - 21 June 1792, Paterson (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - 24 July 1792, Steuart
    - 15 August 1792, Jamieson
    - 20 August 1792, Anonymous (6)
    - 19 September 1792, Rush (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - 27 September 1792, Bonrie
    - 2 November 1792, McDonald
    - 13 November 1792, Collins
    - 13 March 1793, Buist (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - 4 April 1793, Rittenhouse
    - 5 August 1793, Lord Buchan
    - 9 October 1793, Rochefontaine
    - 1 February 1794, Jamieson (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - 10 June 1794, Hunter
    - 12 July 1794, McDonald
    - 30 July 1794, Broom
    - 13 August 1794, Buist (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - 9 September 1794, Lord Buchan
    - 11 September 1794, Oliver, Stephen
    - 12 September 1794, Broom
    - 20 September 1794, Minto, Nanny (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - 24 September 1794, Coventry
    - 1 October 1794, Woofoin
    - 22 October 1794, Littlejohn
    - 24 October 1794, Tod, James (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - 27 October 1794, Young
    - 1 November 1794, McCormick to George Morgan
    - [15 November 1794], S. Smith
    - 14 February 1795, Rochefontaine (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - 3 March 1795, Laurie
    - 24 March 1795, Buist
    - 2 April 1795, Tod, James (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - 23 April 1795, Addison, Alex.
    - 5 May 1795, Minto, Nanny
    - 16 May 1795, Rodgers
    - 6 August 1795, Buist (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - [6 July-28 September 1795], Stockton
    - 27 [?Octo]bre 1795, Woofoin
    - 28 October 1795, Rittenhouse
    - 14 November 1795, B. Smith (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - 3 December 1795, Imlay
    - 21 December 1795, Rittenhouse to Mary Minto
    - 5 September 1796, Minto, Thomas (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - 26 September 1796, Kemp
    - Undated [between 1788 and 1796], Anonymous (4, 7, 8) (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - 29 October [prob. 1790s before late 1796], Chrystie to Mrs. Clark
    - Undated [1790s before late 1796], Skinner
    - After Minto's death (but referring to him) (Box 2, Folder 26)
      - 14 February 1797, Minto, Nanny, to Mrs. Christie (with P.S. 10 March )
      - 16 March 1797, Skelton, Joseph, to Mary Minto
      - 1 July 1797, Snowden, Isaac Jr., to Mary Minto
      - 15 February 1798, Minto, Walter Sr., to Mary Minto
  - 2: Manuscript Notebooks, Diaries, Account Books, etc., All in Minto's hand except the last.
    - 1. [May 1776]: Fragment (perhaps taken from a notepad) containing expenses, receipts, and diary entries from October 1771 (during his stay at Grange Toll in Edinburgh from that date until June 1773) to May 1776., He set off [from London] for Gravesend on 26 May and went on board the Westmoreland on 30 May. This item includes entry for his stay with Mr. Watson in East Rhynd from 2 November 1773 to 11 March 1775 and payments for his engagement with Governor Johnstone's sons from 17 January to 21 May 1776.; 1 small leaf, with recto and verso pages numbered 28 and 29; writing on page 28 only; page 29 blank except for a later note. (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - 2. [March 1779]: Notepad containing expenses incurred and payments received on behalf of the Johnstone boys between 17 January 1776 and 2 December 1778., Last dated receipt is 6 March 1779 for payment of 37 pounds, probably for expenses of the boys, from a Mr. Duff in Cadiz. Minto lists his hypothetical monthly salary through to January 1780 on pages [1]-[2].; 10 small leaves, bound by stitching.
    - 3. [July 1785]: Travel log of a trip within Scotland in July of 1785., Carron, Lithgow, Queen Mary's birthplace, Falkirk, Perth, etc. The only dated stop is Carron on 5 July.; 1 small leaf, with writing on recto only.
    - 4. [July 1786]: "Log-Book & Journal / of a Voyage intended, under God's Providence, / from Greenock to Philadelphia / In the Ship Alexander, Alex. Ritchie Commander, / Kept by W. Minto, Passenger / 1786"., Title on recto of 1st leaf. Leaves 2-52 are numbered (except for leaf 11) on versos from 1 to 50, with each verso and facing recto devoted to a single day of Minto's trip (9 June to 30 July 1786); leaves 53 verso-80 blank and unnumbered. A leaf containing compass directions is inserted in the front of the notebook.; 80 leaves, bound. (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - 5. 1786: Notepad containing a travel log and notes., Notes on Philadelphia and New Jersey; with a few brief comments on New York, Connecticut, Maryland, Delaware, etc.; 8 small leaves, bound with a pin; the first 6 leaves are numbered. (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - 6. [February 1787]: Notepad containing a travel log and notes between September 1786 and 2 February 1787., September 1786 (number of houses in various cities), 26 December 1786 (Albany), 19 January 1787 ("Jaunt to Saratoga"), 2 February 1787 (some Oneida Indian terms).; 8 small leaves, bound with a pin; leaves 2-3 are paginated 2 to 4 beginning with the verso of leaf 2; the rest are unnumbered.
    - 7. Undated [?1782-87]: Notebook of longitudes., For various years from 1600 to 1830, filled only for 1756 and 1770-87; then one for a full but unknown year; other charts based on Greenwich; references to Slop for many calculations in the early 1780s.; 52 leaves, unnumbered, with leaves 1-2, 30-52 blank; leaves 3-29 are written on rectos and/or versos; stubs can be seen between leaves 5 and 6, 15 and 16, 18 and 19, 19 and 20, 21 and 22, 51 and 52. (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - 8. Undated [?perhaps after arriving in America]: "Elements of Algebra" (fragmentary)., 3 leaves folded in half to make a booklet of 6 leaves/12 pages, with writing on pages [1], [3], and [5] only. (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - 9. [1802]: Notebook entitled "Practical Geometry, Trigonometry, and Conick Sections; Trigonometry and Practical Geometry by Walter Minto LLD Transcribed by William Hay, Jr. [?] Princeton NJersey, United States of North America, New World"., Appears to be class notes based originally on Minto's lectures, transcribed by one student and sold to others; other names are George Joness Booth, Jno Crump, George Crump, G. Williams, Stevenson Archer, George Jones; references to Richmond and Manchester, Virginia, and to Western Shore of Maryland; dates included = 26 May 1802 17 August 1802 2 & 3 March 1804.; 85 leaves, bound; beginning on the verso of the 2nd leaf and going to the recto of the 50th leaf the pages are numbered 2-95; from there to the end the pages are mostly blank; many additions in hands other than the main one. (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - 3: Notes by Minto, In his own hand, all undated.
    - 1. [Must have been written after he arrived in America in 1786]: "To the Citizens of America"., Appears to be the beginning of a draft of a speech; gives reasons for emigrating to America: "his heart was warm in the cause of America" and "he thought he could be more useful & more happy here than at home."; 2 leaves folded to make a booklet of 8 small pages, with writing on pages [1]-[4] only. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - 2. Undated: List of surnames with some initials of first names., 1 leaf folded to make 4 pages, with writing on all 4.
    - 3. Undated: List of books., 1 leaf folded to make 4 pages, with writing on all 4.
    - 4. Undated: Notes on story of David, youngest son of Jesse., 1 leaf, with writing on both sides.
    - 5. Undated: List of 15 topics, political or historical, Perhaps intended for speeches like 1 above.; 1 leaf, with writing on both sides.
  - 4: Documents from Minto's time
    - 1. 16 July 1757: Extract from the Baptismal Record of Leghorn [= Livorno in Italy] for 8 April 1739 for Anna Elisabetta, daughter of Capitano Daniello di [P]uglielmo Dousuord di Londra and Marg. d'And. Par[?]ment di Livorno, Elisabetta later became Mrs. Slop: see letter of Minto to Johnstone dated 23 November 1778. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - 2. 15 December 1768 to 15 December 1769: Reading card for the library of the University of Edinburgh, Housed in Graphics Division.
    - 3. 1771:, Invitation from Adam Ferguson to Walter Minto (perhaps to attend a lecture by Ferguson)
    - 4. 24 January 1776: Testimonial (in Latin) by James Robertson of Minto's study at the University of Edinburgh between 1768 and 1771., Minto called a scholar and citizen of the library; in 1768 he studied Latin, in 1769 Logic and Latin, in 1770 Natural Philosophy, Logic, Latin and Greek, in 1771 Moral Philosophy under professors of arts and sciences) and in 1775 (when he studied Moral Philosophy and Rhetoric).
    - 5. 25 November 1778: Statements by two doctors in Pisa, Carlo Barsanti and Domenico Cappucci, about John Johnstone's health, In Italian; with two notarizations in Latin, 1 December 1778. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - 6. 30 November 1778: Certificate of good conduct of Walter Minto, in company with John Johnstone, by Conte Cosimo Agostini., In Italian; with two notarizations in Latin, 1 December 1778.
    - 7. 1 December 1778:, Certificate of good conduct for Walter Minto by Jacopo Andrea Tommasini, professor of mathematics at University of Pisa.; In Italian; notarized.
    - 8. 2 December 1778: Receipt for 20 sequins from "William" Minto for passage from Leghorn to England, signed by Willis Machell.
    - 9. 1 February 1779: Attestation of Walter Minto's good behavior in Pisa by Count Demetrius de Mocenigo, Commissary General of the Navy in Italy for the Empress of Russia, Pisa., In French. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - 10. 13 March 1779: Attestation by Jean Baptiste Poirel, French vice consul, that Minto was put at liberty in Cadix on 23 February [1779], signed by Poirel at "consulat general de France a Cadix" on 13 March 1779., Specifically, that Minto, who was made a prisoner of war on the English ship "Le Westmoreland" by the French ship "Le Destin", passed from Cadiz to Genes [= Genoa] on the "Paquebot" Hollandais called "Le Postillou" commanded by Joseph Dodero.; In French.
    - 11. 18 April 1782: Bill of lading for a box of books, Port of Livorno., Minto's name is not on this, but rather Reverend Padre Ockelli; mentions journey to Ostend, signed Giorgio Bagovich, Dice Epene.; In Italian.
    - 12. 11 June 1782: (Florence) Passport for Minto for passage through Germany, signed by Sir Horace Mann., Housed in Broadsides under Great Britain, Florentine Legation.
    - 13. 3 February 1786: Diploma from the University of Aberdeen for the degree of LL.D. for Walter Minto., Housed in Oversize Manuscripts.
    - 14. 20 May 1786: Certificate of Walter Minto's membership in the Orange Society, Edinburgh, signed by Selkirk Steuart, president, and James Wright, secretary.
    - 15. 7 April 1787: Invitation to Walter Minto to attend Columbia College commencement on the Tuesday following (April 10). (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - 16. 1787 [day and month not filled in yet, but probably between March, when first contact was made with Minto, and May, when school opened]: Draft of an agreement between Minto and the trustees of Erasmus Hall in Flatbush for his services as principal of the Hall., Minto was at Flatbush for circa six months before October 1787.
    - 17. 24 July 1787: Minto's certificate of U.S. naturalization, New York
    - 18. [September 1788]: Draft of a proposal, Proposed by Minto to give up 5 pounds of his salary to purchase a medal to be given by the trustees and faculty of the College for the best dissertation on either of 2 topics: the unlawfulness and impolicy of capital punishment and the unlawfulness and impolicy of African slavery (date from Eisenhart, pp. 290-91).
    - 19. 17 January 1789: Certificate of membership in the American Philosophical Society, signed by B. Franklin, John Ewing, Wm. White, and David Rittenhouse and witnessed by James Hutchinson, R. Patterson, Sam. Magan, and Jn. Vaughan. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - 20. 1 December 1790: Bond of Matthew Clarke to Minto for 160 pounds
    - 21. 22 October 1792: Certificate of membership in the St. Andrew's Society of New York., Housed in Small Broadsides under S.
    - 22. 6 May 1793: Indenture between Walter Minto and the Congregation for 2 pews in the Presbyterian meeting house, Princeton.
    - 23. 6 July 1795: Memorandum of an agreement between Benjamin Smith and Walter Minto., Smith was one of the executors of the will of Samuel [T]ucker, deceased. Agreement "not to expose to sale" the house and land now in Minto's possession and that Minto will execute a bond for 590 pounds to be paid 1/3 on 1 October 1795 the other 2/3 in 4 equal annual payments beginning 1 October 1796.
    - 24. 28 September 1795, 1796[with "six" written over a "five," but day and month are torn away]: Part 1: Bond of indemnity by Minto to Richard Stockton for 1180 pounds, with additional stipulations, with Thomas P. Johnsone, among others, as witness. Part 2: Some sort of codicil by Mary Skelton [Minto], executrix of Minto's last will (he being deceased), probably asking to have debt set aside, with Elizabeth Skelton as witness (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - 25. 1 October 1795: Note beginning "Doctor Minto sined a Bond in conjunction with Richard Stockton to [T]uckers Executors" for 590 pounds., With payment schedule on reverse through 1 October 1799 (see item 9 above).; This note was found with Stockton letter in Series I, sub-series 1 above, and is clearly connected with it in subject matter, but it is not in the same hand, and it is uncertain whether the two were originally together in the Minto donation.
    - 26. 2 May 1796: Bond of Minto to Robert Armstrong for 200 pounds., With notes of repayment on back from Mary Minto in 4 installments (1797-98), the last of which has the name of Josiah Skelton (Mary Minto's older brother) on it; with receipt from Armstrong dated 4 May 1796 for a piece of paper mentioned in the bond.
    - 27. 3 May 1796, 4 May 1796: Statement and release of quitclaim between Robert Armstrong and his slave Tony., Part 1: Copy of statement made on 30 April 1796 that Robert Armstrong brought before 2 justices and 2 overseers of the poor his slave Tony, sound of mind, etc. (original filed in Clerk's office of Middlesex County on 3 May 1796). Part 2: Release by Armstrong of quitclaim to Tony.; One leaf, with writing on the recto only.
    - 28. 4 May 1796: Bond of John Duryie and Toney to Minto for 200 pounds., John Duryie and Toney both free black men (but Toney late a slave to Robert Armstrong, from whom Minto had previously bought him for 100 pounds, as this document says). Bond stipulates that if Toney binds himself to Minto for 6 years and 5 months and carries out all lawful commands, then the debt will be extinguished. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - 29. [October 1796 = the week after 21 October ]: Draft of obituary for Minto., 2 leaves sewn together, with writing only on pages [1] and [4]
    - 30. 8 November 1796, 9 November 1796: Board of Trustees of the College of New Jersey directs Enos Kelley to call on Minto's executor and retrieve the books, public stock, cash, etc. that Minto had as Treasurer of the College. Receipt by Enos Kelley to Mary Minto for the above items., One leaf, with writing on the recto only.
    - 31. 23 May 1801: Bill of lading., For one box, shipped from Leith to New York on the Russell, directed to Mrs. Minto, to be delivered to Mrs. Chrystie of New York for payment; contents unknown to Rowland Gibbs, master of the Russell [probably sent by the Mintos in Scotland; cf. letters of Nanny Minto to Mrs. Chrystie dated 1797 and of Walter Minto Sr. to Mary Minto dated 1798]
- II: Walter Minto Skelton (1804-48) and Family
  - 1: Correspondence
    Correspondence from 1780 to 1813 (and possibly to 1824), primarily to or from Mary Skelton Minto (died late 1824). Correspondence from 1824 to 1843 primarily to or from Walter M. Skelton (died 1848). Later correspondence chiefly concerning Boyd family.
    - 18 October [probably before 1780], Skelton, M[ary], to Betsey Skelton (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - 4 March 1780-6 April 1780, Invitations, Filed in Series II, sub-series 6.
    - 17 February 1781, Invitation, Filed in Series II, sub-series 6.
    - [a few days before 19 November 1781], Mrs. S[cudder] to her husband
    - 24 June 1782--[probably mid-1780s], Invitations, Filed in Series II, sub-series 6.
    - [1788-1789], Minto, Walter, to Miss [Mary] Skelton, Filed in Series I, sub-series 1.
    - 7 October [probably 1789 though could be later], Minto, M[ary], to Walter Minto, Filed in Series I, sub-series 1.
    - 21 December 1795, Rittenhouse to Mary Minto, Filed in Series I, sub-series 1.
    - 14 February 1797 (with P.S. 10 March 1797), Minto, Nanny, to Mrs. Christie, Filed in Series I, sub-series 1.
    - 16 March 1797, Skelton, Joseph, to Mary Minto, Filed in Series I, sub-series 1.
    - 1 July 1797, Snowden to Mary Minto, Filed in Series I, sub-series 1.
    - 15 February 1798, Minto, Walter, Sr., to Mary Minto, Filed in Series I, sub-series 1.
    - 17 July 1799, Anonymous to Mary Minto (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - 6 February 1800, Garcia del Rio to Drake
    - 1 December 1802, Gamble to Detargny (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - 7 December 1805, Chrystie, John, to Mary Minto
    - 2 February 1807, Chrystie, John, to Mary Minto
    - 4 May 1808, Chrystie, John, to Mary Minto
    - 24 October 1808, Gibbes to Mary Minto (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - 22 January 1810, Chrystie, M, to Mary Minto
    - 14 February 1811, Hopkins to Mary Minto
    - 19 January 1813, Hopkins to Mary Minto
    - Undated, [probably after 1796 and perhaps after 1807, before late 1824], Chrystie, M., to Mary Minto (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Undated, [probably after 1796 but not clear how long after; before late 1824], Cuthbert to Mary Minto
    - Undated, [probably after 1796 but not clear how long after; before late 1824], [Cuthbert] to Mary Minto (a draft of the preceding)
    - 27 June 1824, Skelton, Walter Minto, to John Skelton (appears to be a draft, or else the letter was not sent) (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - 18 August 1824, Maclean to WMS
    - 29 September 1824, Skelton, W. M., to Anonymous (draft)
    - 20 January 1825, Skelton, Joseph, to WMS
    - 2 February 1826, Skelton, W. M., to Mary Skelton
    - 6 February 1826, Invitation to Mr. [Walter] Skelton, Filed in Series II, sub-series 6.
    - 22 March 1827, White, Elizabeth, to WMS
    - 8 July 1831, Skelton, W. M., to John Lourey (copy) (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - [received 25 July 1831], Committee of the Princeton Blues to WMS
    - 14 January 1832, Skelton, Ann, to WMS
    - 6 February 1832, Skelton, W. M., to Sarah Skelton
    - 8 February 1834 Invitation to Ann Skelton, Filed in Series II, sub-series 6.
    - February 1843, Invitation to W.M. Skelton & Lady, Filed in Series II, sub-series 6.
    - [?2]4 March [18]72, Ryder to Ann Skelton (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - 17 February 1887, Rayburn to Hannah P. Boyd
    - 7 January [18]98, Earhart, Harry B., to W.M. Boyd
    - 30 March 1906, Duffy to Hill (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - 11 September 1915, K., H.L., to Elizabeth [Boyd]
    - 11 January 1930, Skelton, Ann, to Mary Boyd (transcript of spirit message enclosed in next letter)
    - 12 January 1930, Robb to Elizabeth Boyd
    - 7 April 1931, Thorsen to Elizabeth Boyd
    - 18 November 1937, White, Marie Earhart, to Elizabeth Boyd (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - 24 August 1938, Jack[s]on to Elizabeth Boyd
    - 2 May 1939, White, Marie Earhart, to Elizabeth Boyd
    - 6 September 1940, White, Marie Earhart, to Elizabeth Boyd
  - 2. Prose Writings and Poetry
    - Notebooks
      - In WMS's hand
        - 1822-1827, "Original Pieces / in Poetry and Prose. / 1824" (title, on page 3), A mixture of verse and prose pieces. The first item is a poem entitled "To the Memory of A Mother." At ends of pieces there are frequently dates, usually consecutive (e.g., August 10, August 14, September 5 1824, March 5 1825, July 1822, January 1825, April 2nd 1825, July 8th 1825, January 9th 1825, January 1826, June 1827), followed by initials or names (e.g., AHDH, my mother, MBW, Miss S. Bayley, MW, TA-n, DB), perhaps referring to people to whom Skelton has shown the pieces; occasionally the note "Published" appears. Most prose pieces parallel those found in Orations, Lectures, and Essays below.; 189 pages (with numbering beginning with "1" on page [4]); pages 116-89 are blank. (Box 3, Folder 19)
        - 1824, "Extracts-1824 / Walter M. Skelton's" (title page), Primarily verse, with attributions at the ends of each piece. The cover and title page both have "W M Skelton" stamped on them.; 190 pages. (Box 3, Folder 20)
        - Undated, ca. 1824-27, "Extracts / Skelton's" (title page), Primarily verse, but a few prose pieces: a series of quotations, with name or source at the end of each. 96 pages, with 60-64, 68-69, and 74-96 blank. (Box 3, Folder 21)
      - In other hands
        - 1818-[183]4, lecture notes, Notes from 8 lectures on history (both general and ancient), some with questions appended; followed by (and occasionally interspersed with) verse. On front cover: "M [W] McAllister / Princeton College / Nassau Hall / Newjersey / January 9, 1818 / in the 42 year of the Amer / ican Independence." On page 3: "Conemaugh Loyalhanna," "Conemaugh" again, "T.W. Simpson," "Theodore Simpson," "Conemaugh Thomas Chrystie Skelton" (this last upside down in bottom margin); on page 52: "Conamaugh May 18[3]4."; 50 pages (numbered beginning with 3 and going to 52), covered with boards; appears to be same hand throughout. (Box 3, Folder 22)